Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Diamond Information Center Vertical File, 1930s-1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Vertical File, (78 boxes)
  - [100. Diamond Jewelry]
    - [162. Famous Diamonds (Individual)]
      - 162.AUS. Austrian Yellow Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.1.B. Black Orloff (Box 23)
      - 162.BLA. Black Star (Box 23)
      - 162.BLU. Blue diamonds (Box 23)
      - 162.BLU. Blue Lily (Box 23)
      - 162.3.B. Briolette of India (Box 23)
      - 162.4. Bouelle Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.2.B. Braganza (Box 23)
      - 162.CAR. Cartier Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.1. Louis Cartier Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162. Colenso Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.1.C. Cleveland Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.CON. Constantin (Box 24)
      - 162.2.C. Copenhagen Blue (Box 24)
      - 162.3.C. Cuban Capital Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.C. Cullinan (Box 24)
      - 162.5.C. Cumberland Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.1.D. Darya-i-nur (Box 24)
      - 162.DEB. De Beers Diamond, (2 folders) (Box 24)
      - 162.2.D. Deepdene Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.DES. Desert Star (Box 24)
      - 162.DIA. Diamond Arrow (Box 24)
      - 162.3.D. Dresden Green Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.D.B.W. Dresden White (Box 24)
      - 162.DUD. Star of South Africa Diamond (Dudley) (Box 24)
      - 162.DUT. Du Toit (Box 24)
      - 162.1.E. Earth Star Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.EMP. Empress Josephine Brooch (Box 24)
      - 162.2.E. English Dresden Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162. Engraved diamonds (Box 24)
      - 162.EUG-BLUE. Eugene Blue Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.EUG. Eugenie Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.4.E. Eureka Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.5.E. Excelsior Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162. Fifty Years of Aeroflot, 232-carat Russian diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.1.F. Flame of Gold Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.FLA. Flaming Star (Box 24)
      - 162.2.F. Florentine Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.1.G. Gaby Deslys Diamond (Box 24)
      - 162.GEM. Geminies (One and Two) (Box 25)
      - 162.2.G. Golconda d'Or Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.GOL. Golden Door (Box 25)
      - 162.3.GM. Golden Maharajah (Box 25)
      - 162.4.C. La Grande Couer d'Africa (Box 25)
      - 162.3.G. Grand Condé Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.4.G. Great Chrysanthemum Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.GRE. Great Harry Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.5.G. Great Mogul Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.GTD. Great Table Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.G. Grima Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.GUG. Guggenheim Diamonds (Box 25)
      - 162.GUI. Guise Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.HAL. Halphen Red Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.HA. Harlequin (Box 25)
      - 162.HIS. Histories of some famous diamonds (Box 25)
      - 162.HOPE. Hope Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.IDO. Idol's Eye Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.IND. Star of Independence (Box 25)
      - 162.IND. Indian Diamond (Box 25)
      - 162.IV. Ivory Moon (Box 25)
      - 162.JAC. Jacob Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.JAH. Jahangir Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.JEH. Jehangir Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.JON. Jonker Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.JUB. Jubilee Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.JUN. June Briolette Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.KEN. Kenmore Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.KHE. Khedive Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.KIM. Kimberley Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.KOH. Koh-i-noor Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.KRG. Kruger Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.KRU. Krupp Diamonds (Box 26)
      - 162.LAB. La Belle Helene (Box 26)
      - 162.LES. Lesotho Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.LIG. Light of Peace Diamond (Box 26)
      - 162.MAX. Maximilian Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.MAZ. Mazarin, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - 162.McF. McFarlin Canary Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.MEI. Meister Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.MOO. Moon of Baroda and other moon diamonds (Box 27)
      - 162.MOO. Moon of the Mountains Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.MOU. Mounce Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.MS. Mountain of Splendour (Box 27)
      - 162.NAS. Nassak Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.NAV. Navangar Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.NEP. Nepal Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.NIA. Niarchos (Box 27)
      - 162.NIZ. Nizam Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.NOS. North Star Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.NUR. Nur-ul-ain Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.OPP. Oppenheimer Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.ORL. Orloff Diamond, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - 162.ORT. Ortlepp Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PAS. Pasha Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PAU. Paul I Red Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PIG. Pigott Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.POL. Polar Star Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.POR. Porter-Rhodes (Box 27)
      - 162.POR. Regent of Portugal Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PORT. Portuguese Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PRE. Premier Rose Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PRI. Prince Edward of York Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PRI. Princie Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.FRE. Queen Fredrica Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.QUE. Queen of Holland Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.REG. Regent Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.ROJ. Rojtman Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.RUG. Russian diamonds general (Box 27)
      - 162.SAN. Sancy Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.SHA. Shah Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.PER. Shah of Persia Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.SHE. Shephard Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.SIE. Sierra Leone stones (Box 27)
      - 162.SOL. Sol et d'Or (Box 27)
      - 162.ASI. Star of Asia (Box 27)
      - 162.DEN. Star of Denmark (Box 27)
      - 162.STA. Star of the East Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.EST. Star of Este Diamond (Box 27)
      - 162.SIE. Star of Sienna Leone Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.SOU. Star of the South Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.STA. Star of Texas (Box 28)
      - 162.STE. Stewart Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.SUL. Sultan of Moracco Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.SUN. Sunrise Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.TAB. Tabert Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162. Taylor Heart (Box 28)
      - 162. Taylor-Burton (Box 28)
      - 162.TIF. Tiffany Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.TRA. Transvaal Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.TUR. Turkey Diamond I and II (Box 28)
      - 162.VAR. President Vargas (Box 28)
      - 162.VIC. Victoria Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.WAL. Walska Heart-Walska Briolette (Box 28)
      - 162.WHI. White Saxon Brilliant (Box 28)
      - 162.WIL. Williamson Pink Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.WIN. Winston Diamond - Jagersfontein (Box 28)
      - 162.WIT. Wittelsbacher Diamond (Box 28)
      - 162.WOY. Woyie River Diamond (Box 28)
    - 163. Color Chart of Diamonds - Modern Jeweler (Box 28)
    - 163.COL. Colored diamonds (Box 28)
    - 163. Diamonds - Lust, Love and Power (Box 28)
    - 164. Unnamed diamonds (Box 28)
    - 170.DOL. Colleen Moore's Doll House (Box 28)
    - 171. Jewelry Exhibitions [including Diamonds International Awards]
      - 171.ADO. Art of Personal Adornment (exhibition) (Box 28)
      - 171.AGE. Ageless Diamonds (exhibition) (Box 28)
      - 171.ART. Art in Jewelry (exhibition) (Box 28)
      - 171.BIR. Exhibition of Gemstones & Jewellery (Birmingham, England, 1960) (Box 29)
      - 171.BRI. British exhibition in New York (Box 29)
      - 171. Brooklyn Museum, Greek Gold, 1966 (Box 29)
      - 171.BRU. Brussels-World Fair Exhibit, 1958 (Box 29)
      - 171.COO. Nineteenth Century Jewelry, Cooper Union Museum, 1955 (Box 29)
      - 171.COU. Court of Jewels, 1949 (Box 29)
      - 171.CRY. Crystal Palace exhibition, 1851 (Box 29)
      - 171.DIA. Diamond in Art & Industry (Box 29)
      - 171.DIA. Diamonds International Awards, miscellaneous (Box 29)
      - 171.1.INT. Diamonds International Academy (Box 29)
      - 171.INT. Diamonds International Awards (Box 29)
      - 171.INT. Diamonds International Awards (entrants), 1968 (Box 29)
      - 171.INT. Diamonds International Awards (entrants), 1969-1978 and 1982, (11 folders) (Box 30)
      - 171.INT. Diamonds International Awards (records) (Box 30)
        Note: Diamonds International Awards material continues in Box 32.
      - 171.LIS. Listings of exhibitions (Box 31)
      - 171.LON. London, Jewel of the Year, 1962 (Box 31)
      - 171.LOU. Ten Centuries of French Jewelry, Louvre, 1962 (Box 31)
      - 171.RAN. Rand Easter exhibits, 1963-1967 (Box 31)
    - 172. Jewelry Competitions
      - 172.COM. Jewelry competitions [general] (Box 31)
      - 172.CP and 172.PEA. Cultured pearl contests, (2 folders) (Box 31)
      - 172.DER-F. Diamond engagement ring competition, France, 1969 (Box 31)
      - 172.DIA. Diamonds-International Awards Catalogs (Box 31)
      - 172. Diamonds-Today Collection, Royal Ontario Museum, 1973 (Box 31)
      - 172.ITA. Italy (Box 31)
      - 172.JAP. Japan engagement ring competition (Box 31)
      - 172.JAP. Jewelry competition - Japan (Box 31)
      - 172. London contest, jewelry design, 1970 (Box 31)
      - 173.AMS. Amsterdam diamond exhibition, June 1949 (Box 31)
      - 173.DEB. De Beers exhibit, World's Columbian Exp. Chicago, 1893 (Box 31)
      - 173.GJF. Golden Jubilee Fashion Show, 1948 (Box 31)
      - 173.IDS. International Diamond Show, Amsterdam, 1957 (Box 31)
      - 173.N.Y.W. New York World's Fair, 1939 (Box 31)
    - 171.INT. Diamonds International Awards (booklets, 1958-1978, and medals), (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - 200. Diamond Markets [General]
    - 200. Diamond marketing (Box 32)
    - 210. General marketing (Box 32)
    - 210.SMU. Diamond Smuggling: a chapter from The Smugglers, by Timothy Green, 1969 (Box 32)
    - 211.DIA. The Diamond Industry, by L.J. Burke, Diamant, 1967 (Box 32)
    - 211.OPP. The Marketing of Rough Diamonds, by P.J. Oppenheimer, 1967 (Box 32)
    - 212.BBB. Better Business Bureaus (Box 32)
    - 212. Consumer research: the gem diamond, 1960 (Box 32)
    - 212.NYT. Diamonds Aren't Necessarily Forever, by Anthony Carthew (Box 33)
    - 213. Ernest Oppenheimer (Box 33)
    - 213.EO. Sir Ernest Oppenheimer (Box 33)
    - 213.HO. Harry Oppenheimer, photos (Box 33)
    - 213.LO. Louis Oppenheimer (miscellaneous material) (Box 33)
    - 213.NIC. Nicholas Oppenheimer, Harry's son (Box 33)
    - 213.PJO. Philip J. Oppenheimer (miscellaneous material) (Box 33)
    - 213.SPI. Sidney Spiro (Box 33)
    - 213. Women in diamond marketing (Box 33)
    - 214.JCK.1-4. Jewelers Circular-Keystone Annual Reports on the Diamond Industry, 1925-1969, (4 folders)
      - 214.JCK-1. 1925-1969 (Box 33)
    - 220.GHA. Ghana diamonds (Box 33)
    - 220.RUS. Russian sales agreement with DeBeers (Box 33)
    - 221.DTC. Diamond Cutter Buys Diamonds at DTC in Kimberly, photo story circa 1945 (Box 33)
    - 222. Rough Diamond Sales--Statistics and Reports (Box 33)
    - 222.1. Annual Report .. Diamond Industry, prepared by Jewelers Circular Keystone (Box 34)
    - 222.1. Gem stones, U.S. Bureau of Mines (Box 34)
    - 223.CSO. Evolution of the central selling organization for diamonds (Box 34)
    - 223.De B. De Beers Consolidated Mines, Ltd. (miscellaneous articles) (Box 34)
    - 223.MON. Monopoly of industry--De Beers (Box 34)
    - 223.SLE. Government Diamond Office--Sierra Leone (Box 34)
    - 230. Wholesale Diamond Marketing
      - 230.DOB. Dobson Diamond Distributor (Box 34)
      - 230. Whole Sales--47th Street (Box 34)
    - 231. Sales methods (Box 34)
    - 232. Statistics of Diamond Marketing (Box 35)
      - 232.TEE. Teenage statistics and reports (Box 35)
      - 232.1.ISR. Israel--imports and exports (Box 35)
      - 232.1.US. Diamond importants (U.S.) (Box 35)
    - 233.1. 47th Street (NYC) Diamond Center (Box 35)
    - 233.DCA. Diamond Council of America (Box 35)
    - 233.1. Diamond Corporation of America (Box 35)
    - 233.1.DMI. Diamond Manufacturers & Importers (Box 35)
    - 233.1.HAT. Hatton Garden Diamond Service (Box 35)
    - 233.HFO. Harry F. Oppenheimer (miscellaneous articles) (Box 35)
    - 233? International Diamond Sales, Antwerp (Box 35)
    - 233.1.MAI. Maiden Lane (Box 35)
    - 240. Diamond Retailing
      - 240. Gemological Institute of America (Box 35)
      - 240. How to Sell More Diamonds [booklet] (Box 35)
      - 240. Retail Prices .. quarterly surveys (Box 35)
      - 241.APP. Appraisals (Box 35)
      - 241. Buying diamonds - retail (Box 36)
      - 241. Department stores .. jewelry departments (Box 36)
      - 241.CLUB. Diamond Club (Box 36)
      - 241.2.CRE. Credit buying (Box 36)
      - 241.INV. Diamonds for investment (Box 36)
      - 241.LEA. Leased departments (Box 36)
      - 241.S. Security in retail stores (Box 36)
      - 242.BL. Black [African-American] market (Box 36)
      - 242.JO. Jewelers Outlook (Box 36)
      - 242.2.PRI. Upward swing in diamond prices (Box 36)
      - 242. Retail Jewelers Survey, 1954-1955, 1960, 1966-1968 (Box 36)
      - 242. Retail sales .. statistics and reports (Box 36)
      - 242.1. Statistics and reports, annual (Box 36)
      - 242.2.JCK. Typical engagement ring sale, Jeweler's Circular-Keystone, October 1969 (Box 36)
      - 242.2.TEENS. Teenage market (Box 36)
      - 243. Diamond Retailers -- Organizations
        - 243.AGS. American Gem Society (Box 36)
        - 243.BEL. Leon R. Bellis (Box 37)
        - 243.HEF. Elleard B. Heffern, Inc., St. Louis (Box 37)
        - 243.JBT. Jewelers Board of Trade (Box 37)
        - 243.1.CAL. California Retail Jewelers Association (Box 37)
        - 243.1.CONN. Connecticut Retail Jewelers Association (Box 37)
        - 243.1.JIC. Jewelry Industry Council (Box 37)
        - 243.1.JVC. Jewelers Vigilance Committee (Box 37)
        - 243.1.RJA. Retail Jewelers of America (Box 37)
      - 243.2. Diamond Retailers -- Individual
        - 243.2.ARG. Argenzio Brothers (Box 37)
        - 243.2.ARGO. Argo & Lehne (Box 37)
        - 243.2.BAL. Henry B. Ball Co. (Box 37)
        - 243.2. Myer B. Barr (Box 37)
        - 243.2.BEN. Bennett Brothers (Box 37)
        - 243.2. Bixler's (Box 37)
        - 243.2.BS&G. Black, Starr & Gorham (Box 37)
        - 243.2.CAL. J.E. Caldwell & Co. (Box 37)
        - 243.2.CAR. Cartier (Box 37)
        - 243.2.HAR. Hardy & Ames (Pittsburgh) (Box 37)
        - 243.2.BUC. Bucherer (Box 38)
        - 243.2.CHA. Chaumet (Box 38)
        - 243.2.COO. F.J. Cooper (Box 38)
        - 243.2.DON. Donavan & Seamans Co. (Los Angeles) (Box 38)
        - 243.2.EVE. Arthur A. Everts Co. (Box 38)
        - 243.2.GAL. Galt & Bro., Inc. (Box 38)
        - 243.2.GAR. Garrards (Britain's Crown Jewelers) (Box 38)
        - 243.2.GOOD. A.D. Goodman & Bros. (Box 38)
        - 243.2.GOR. Gordon Traditional Stores (Houston, Texas) (Box 38)
        - 243.2.HAA. Haack (Box 38)
        - 243.2.HAN. Hand of Gold Originals (Box 38)
        - 243.2.HIM. Marvin Hime (Box 38)
        - 243.2.HUD. J.L. Hudson (Box 38)
        - 243.2.JAC. Mermod Jaccard King (Box 38)
        - 243.2.JBS. Jewel Box Stores (Box 38)
        - 243.2.JES. Jessop & Sons (Box 38)
        - 243.2.KAT. Katz & Lourie (Box 38)
        - 243.2.KER. Rene G. Kern (Box 38)
        - 243.2.KIG. C.A. Kiger Co. (Box 38)
        - 243.2.SKL. S. Klein (Box 38)
        - 243.2.KOS. Nat Koslow (Box 38)
        - 243.2.KRA. Sidney Krandall & Sons (Box 38)
        - 243.2.LAM. Lambert Brothers (Box 38)
        - 243.2.LAY. Laykin & Co. (West Coast) (Box 38)
        - 243.2.LEV. Harry Levinson (Box 38)
        - 243.2.LIN. Lindemann Jewelry Co. (San Francisco) (Box 38)
        - 243.2.LINZ. Linz (Dallas, Texas) (Box 38)
        - 243.2.LIT. Litwin Co. (Box 38)
        - 243.2.MAR. Marchal (Box 38)
        - 243.2.MAY. L&C Mayers Co. (Box 38)
        - 243.2.MIS. Miscellaneous Retail Jewelers: Modest Priced Diamonds (Box 38)
        - 243.2.OST. Ostier, Inc. (Box 38)
        - 243.2.PAR. Parke-Bernet (Auction House) (Box 38)
        - 243.2.PEA. C.D. Peacock (Box 38)
        - 243.2.PER. Perel & Lowenstein (Box 39)
        - 243.2.PLA. John Plain & Co. (Box 39)
        - 243.2.PRI. Primavesi & Kaufmann (Box 39)
        - 243.2.SEL. Selco, Inc. (Box 39)
        - 243.2.SIM. Simon's (Box 39)
        - 243.2.SOG. Arthur C. Sogno Co. Jewelers (R.C.A. Building, New York) (Box 39)
        - 243.2.S&F. Spritzer & Fuhrmann (Box 39)
        - 243.2.STE. Sterling Silversmith Guild (Box 39)
        - 243.2.STE. Hans Stern (Box 39)
        - 243.2.TIF. Tiffany (Box 39)
        - 243.2.TIL. Tillander (Helsinki) (Box 39)
        - 243.2.WAN. Wander & Co. (Box 39)
        - 243.2.ZALE. Zale Corporation (Box 39)
    - 250. Advertising and Promotion (U.S.)
      - 250.COU. Courtenay Jamison Advertising (Box 39)
      - 250. Lapidary Reporter, 6 September 1969 (Box 39)
      - 250.1. Christmas (Box 39)
      - 251.1. Ethyl tie in (Box 39)
      - 251.2. Gift newspaper ads (local) (Box 39)
      - 252.GEN. Gene Moore (Tiffany display man) (Box 39)
      - 252.WAN. Wanamaker displays (Box 39)
      - 252.1. Display: diamond tools and dies (Box 39)
      - 252.3. Diamond rooms, (2 folders) (Box 40)
      - 253.1. Bridal shows (Box 40)
      - 252.4.CUT. Cutting demonstrations (Box 40)
      - 255.DOR. Dorothy Lewis Dolls, (2 folders) (Box 40)
      - 255.DOR. Dorothy Lewis Dolls-- Little Queens and Big Diamonds (Box 40)
      - 255.ENG. Engagement ring promotion material (Box 40)
      - 255.2. Promotion to stores (Box 40)
      - 255.2. Local newspaper advertising (Box 40)
      - 255.2. Kingsley Gift Book (Box 40)
    - 260. Advertising and Promotion (abroad)
      - 260.AUS. Austrialia (Box 41)
      - 260. Canada (Box 41)
      - 260.CAN. Canadian Jewelers Association (Box 41)
      - 261. Canadian Diamond Surveys, 1956-1967 (Box 41)
      - 262. France (Box 41)
      - 263. Germany (Box 41)
      - 264. Great Britain (Box 41)
      - 268. Advertising and promotion in New Zealand and Australia (Box 41)
    - 271. Jewel robberies and fingerprinting (Box 41)
    - 272. Insurance for diamonds, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - 274. Excise taxes (Box 41)
    - 273. Better Business Bureau (Box 41)
  - 300. Diamond Jewelry Manufacturing
    - 320. Manufacture of jewelry (general) (Box 41)
    - 321.BAL. Ballard & Ballard (Box 41)
    - 321.ELE. Electroforming gold (Box 41)
    - 321. Mountings and settings (Box 42)
    - 321.SET. Diamond setting (Box 42)
    - 322. Finishes, Gold Filled Mfgr. Assoc. (Box 42)
    - 322. Metals in jewelry (Box 42)
    - 330. Manufacturers and Designers
      - 330.ALB. Gilbert Albert (Box 42)
      - 330.ANN. Anneke Schat (Box 42)
      - 330.ANT. Barbara Anton (Box 42)
      - 330.BAL. Charles Baldinger (designer) (Box 42)
      - 330.BEC. Friedrich Becker (Box 42)
      - 330.BLA. Roger Blanton (designer) (Box 42)
      - 330.BOH. Bohnenburger (Box 42)
      - 330.BRA. Braque (Box 42)
      - 330.BRY. Irena Brynner (Box 42)
      - 330.BUC Nadja Buckley (Box 42)
      - 330.CIP. Aldo Cipullo (designer) (Box 42)
      - 330.COL. Helen Fletcher Collins (Box 42)
      - 330.DAL. Salvador Dali/Dali Jewelry, (1 of 3 folders) (Box 42)
      - 330.DAL. Salvador Dali/Dali Jewelry, (2-3 of 3 folders) (Box 43)
      - 330.DIN. Jean Dinh Van (designer, Cartier's) (Box 43)
      - 330.DIO. Christian Dior (precious jewelry) (Box 43)
      - 330.DON. John Donald (Box 43)
      - 330.DUQ. Tony Duquette (designer) (Box 43)
      - 330.ERM. Engagement ring manufacturers (Box 43)
      - 330.FAB. Faberge (Box 43)
      - 330.FEA. Feature Engagement Ring Co. (Box 43)
      - 330.FRE. French jewelers and designers (Box 43)
      - 330.G-L. Gensler-Lee (Box 43)
      - 330.GEY. Anne Geyer (Box 43)
      - 330.GRI. Andrew Grima (Box 43)
      - 330.HAM. Hamilton Watch Co. (Box 43)
      - 330.HEA. George Headley (Box 43)
      - 330.HEY. Oscar Heyman (Box 43)
      - 330.HOLZ. Nathan Holz (Box 43)
      - 330.ITA. Italian jewelers (Box 43)
      - 330.JAB. Jabel Ring Manufacturers (Box 44)
      - 330.J. Japanese jewelry designers (Box 44)
      - 330.JOS. Mrs. Joan Castle Joseff (Box 44)
      - 330.JOY. Isabelle Joyce (Box 44)
      - 330.K&B. Karlan & Bleicher, Inc. (Box 44)
      - 330.KIG. C.A. Kiger (Box 44)
      - 330.KOV. Marc Koven (Box 44)
      - 330.KRU. Mary Kruming (Box 44)
      - 330.KUNZ. Dr. George F. Kunz (Box 44)
      - 330.LAL. Ganeshi Lall & Son (Box 44)
      - 330.LAN. Kenneth L. Lane (costume jewelry) (Box 44)
      - 330.LIN. Peter Lindeman (Box 44)
      - 330.LIN. Robert Lindemann (Box 44)
      - 330.OGD. Ogden (Box 44)
      - 330.OSM. Louis Osman (designer) (Box 44)
      - 330.PEA. Erwin Pearl (Box 44)
      - 330.PER. Sigurd Persson (Box 44)
      - 330.PON. Pond Ring Co. (Box 44)
      - 330. Fulvio Scavia (Box 44)
      - 330.SCH. Seaman Schepps (Box 44)
      - 330.SCH. Mary Schimpff (Box 44)
      - 330.SCH. Jean Schlumbweger (designer) (Box 44)
      - 330.SEA. Sears & Roebuck Diamond Department (Box 45)
      - 330.SIE. Patrick Dennis Sieler (Box 45)
      - 330.TRA. Traub Ring Co. (Box 45)
      - 330.VAN. Van Cleef & Arpels (Box 45)
      - 330.WEB. David Webb (Box 45)
      - 330.WER. Jack M. Werst (Box 45)
      - 330.WIN. Harry Winston, (2 folders) (Box 45)
      - 330.WOO. J.R. Wood (Box 46)
    - 330.1. References to diamonds in literature (Box 46)
    - 330.2. Design information: titanium, nobium and tatalum (Box 46)
    - 331. Manufacturers and designs (Box 46)
    - 332. Manufacturer groups
      - 332.DMI. Diamond Manufacturers & Importers Association (Box 46)
      - 332.GOL. Goldsmith's Hall, London (Box 46)
      - 332.GRA. Granat Brothers .. Manufacturers-Retailers (Box 46)
      - 332.MAN. Manufacturers of Engagement Rings (Box 46)
    - 333. Jewelry Designers
      - 333.ALL. Jane Allen (DIA) (Box 46)
      - 333.AME. American Designers (Box 46)
      - 333.BER. Wesley Bergen (Box 46)
      - 333.BUL. Bulgari (Box 46)
      - 333.DUN. Henry Dunay (Box 46)
      - 333.EMI. Ms. Emis (Box 46)
      - 333.HAY. Maggie Hayes (Box 46)
      - 333.HIS. Yasuhiko Hishida (Box 46)
      - 333.HVO. Theresia Hvorslev (Box 46)
      - 333.ISH. Hikoji Ishii (Box 46)
      - 333.ISR. Leon Israel (Box 47)
      - 333.LUC. Roger Lucas (Box 47)
      - 333.MER. Rex Steele Merten (Dia winner) (Box 47)
      - 333.MIT. Takao Mitsuyasu (Box 47)
      - 333.PET. Hans-Leo Peters (DI Academy) (Box 47)
      - 333.SUZ. Sachiko Suzuki (Box 47)
      - 333.TAK. Kotaku Takabatake (Box 47)
      - 333.WOO. Helen Woodhull (Box 47)
      - 333.YAM. Tsuyoshi Yamada (Box 47)
  - 400. Diamond Cutting
    - 400.LAP. Lapidary Journal (gem cutting magazine) (Box 47)
    - 411.GBR. History of cutting in Great Britain (Box 47)
    - 411.HIS. History of Diamond Cutting (Box 47)
    - 412.AME. American Cut (American School of Diamond Cutting) (Box 47)
    - 412.AMS. Amsterdam Diamond Center (Box 47)
    - 412.ANT. Antwerp Cutting Center (Box 47)
    - 412.BEL. Belgium (Box 47)
    - 412.BER. Socio-Economic Considerations in Shifts of the Diamond-Cutting Industry, Mildred Berman (Box 47)
    - 412.GEN. Location of diamond-cutting industry (Box 47)
    - 412.GEN. Optima article on centers in general (Box 48)
    - 412.HOL. Diamond cutting factories in Holland (Box 48)
    - 412.IDA. Idar Oberstein article (Box 48)
    - 412.IND. India as cutting center (Box 48)
    - 412.ISR. Israel Cutting Center (Box 48)
    - 412.PR. Puerto Rico (cutting center) (Box 48)
    - 414. Cutting theory (Box 48)
    - 421.CUT. Cutting steps--Baumgold (Box 48)
    - 421.CUT. Cutting steps--Photos and negatives (Box 48)
    - 421.EAR. Earth Star steps in cutting at Baumgold Bros. plant (Box 48)
    - 421.ILL. Illustrated Steps in Cutting (Box 48)
    - 421.MAC. Machines for cutting (grinding) (Box 49)
    - 421.MAR. Marking (Box 49)
    - 421.PLA. Plant interiors--Cutting operations (Box 49)
    - 421.POL. Polishing diamonds (Box 49)
    - 421.REP. Replicas of Cutting Steps (Box 49)
    - 421.SAW. Diamond sawing (Box 49)
    - 421.THA. Thailand--Cutting center (Box 49)
    - 422. Cuts & Shapes (general)
      - 422.BAG. Baguette cut (Box 49)
      - 422.BAR. Barion cut (Box 49)
      - 422.BRI. Brilliant cut (Box 49)
      - 422.EME. Emerald cut (Box 49)
      - 422.HEA. Heart cut (Box 49)
      - 422.HIG. Highlight cut (Box 49)
      - 422.HUI. Huisman Brothers cut (Box 49)